Finding Aid for George William Cushing papers and sound recordings, 1942-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- In Our Opinion: recordings of programs, 7 in. reel-to-reel tapes; 7 1/2 ips
  - 1954
    - March 21, 1954 "France" (Box 9)
      (Guests: Father Pierre Poirier (National Chaplain of the Rural Family Movement, Paris), Dr. Donat Gauthier (former Counselor Agent for France))
    - March 28, 1954-"Trip Around the World" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Miss Betty Nelson (Teacher Fordson High School, Dearborn))
    - April 11, 1954 "Situation in Indo-China" (Box 10)
      (Guests: General SAL Marshall (Detroit News Military Critic))
    - April 18, 1954 "Easter Sunday" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Rt. Rev. Richard S. Emrich (Bishop of the Episcopal Diocese of Detroit))
    - May 2, 1954 "Michigan Hospital Week" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Danny Thomas, Mrs. Edward D. Spalding (Detroit Area Council of Hospital Auxiliaries))
    - May 9, 1954 "Trip to Europe" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Joseph Hainline)
    - May 16, 1954 "Armed Forces Day" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Lt. General Emmett O'Donnell (Deputy Chief of Staff, Personnel, United States Air Force))
    - May 23, 1954 "Presbyterian Church", 2 tapes (Box 10)
      (Guests: Rev. Harold Voekel (Chaplain among captured prisoners in Korea), Dr. Charles Leber (General Secretary of Board of Foreign Missions of Presbyterian Church))
    - May 30, 1954 "Decoration Day" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Ellen Guest)
    - June 6, 1954 "United Negro College Fund" (Box 10)
      (Guests: William T. Gossett (Vice President of Ford Motor Company and Chairman of the Steering Committee), Walker L. Cisler (President of the Detroit Edison Company and Chairman of the Drive), Dr. Alonzo G. Moron (President of Hampton Institute Hampton, Virginia))
    - June 27, 1954 "United States Overseas Information Program" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Stephan P. Munsing (Cultural Affairs Officer for U.S. Information Agency in Berlin), Professor Will Grohman (Professor of Fine Arts at Technical University of Berlin and Art Critic American Government Radio Station RIAS in Berlin))
    - July 4, 1954 "Independence Day" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Howard Peckham (Director, William L. Clements Library, Ann Arbor, Michigan), William Sheehan (WJR Newscaster))
    - July 11, 1954 "Trip Around the World" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mrs. Louis Carpenter (Assistant Foreign Student Advisor, Michigan State College))
    - July 18, 1954, "Grand Trunk Railroad", 2 tapes (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Hayward Abelwhite (Greenfield Village), Mr. David Nadeau (Greenfield Village), Frank Edison Smith (Grand Trunk Engineer), John F. Kramer (Station Master at Grand Trunk), John Burrows (Relief Station Master, Grand Trunk), Charles Hawkins (Grand Trunk Conductor), William K. Gibb (Grand Trunk Conductor), Louis A. Harnack (Mount Clemens Station Agent, retired))
    - July 25, 1954 "Indochina" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Jean Beliard (French Counsel))
    - August 1, 1954 "Indochina" (Box 10)
      (Guests: General S.A.L. Marshall (Military Critic of the Detroit News)
      (The surface of the disc was very noisy)
    - August 8, 1954 "Africa" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Rt. Rev. Stephen Tomusange (Assistant Bishop of the Upper Nile), Rev. Stanley Moore (Headmaster of the High School at Gulu), Mrs. Stanley Moore (lay representative of Anglican Congress))
    - August 9, 1954 Africa (cont.) (Box 10)
    - August 15, 1954 "Mediterranean Cruise" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Robert L. Jillson (Redford High School Graduate, Winner of Harold Harding Essay Contest))
    - August 22, 1954 "South American Immunity to Disease" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Dr. Eugene H. Payne (Medical Research Staff Parke Davis and Company))
    - August 29, 1954 "Internships for Foreign Journalists" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Robi Chakravorti (Calcutta, India))
    - September 5, 1954 "Trip to Europe" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. C. J. Huddleston (Executive Vice President, Wabeek State Bank))
    - September 12, 1954 "Michigan State College" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Dr. John A. Hannah (President, Michigan State College))
    - September 19, 1954 "St. Andrew's Youth Movement" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Dr. Paul Rusch (Executive Director, Kiyosato Educational Experiment))
    - September 26, 1954 "St. Lawrence Seaway" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Troy H. Browning (President, T. H. Browning Steanship Lines))
      (part of lead-in announcement missing from disc)
    - October 3, 1954 "Old Mariner's Church" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Reverend Irwin C. Johnson (Rector of St. John's Episcopal Church and acting Rector of Mariner's Church), Mr. George W. Stark (President, Detroit Historical Commission, Senior Warden of Mariner's Church))
    - October 10, 1954 "World Tour" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. William H. Ramsay (Director, Eastern Hemisphere Operations, Parke Davis & Company))
    - October 17, 1954, "Surrender of Lt. Gen. Burgoyne", 2 tapes (Box 10)
      (Guests: Mr. Howard H. Peckham (Director, Clements Library, U of M, Ann Arbor), Jim Vinall (WJR Newscaster))
    - November 7, 1954 "Viet Nam" (Box 10)
      (Guests: Dr. Edward W. Weidner (Professor and Head of Political Science Dept. and Public Administration, MSC), Dr. Wesley R. Fishel (Associate Professor of Political Science, MSC), James H. Denison (Administrative Assistant to President John A. Hannah, Michigan State College))
    - November 14, 1954-"Detroit Police Department" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Superintendent Edwin S. Morgan, Commissioner Edward S. Piggins)
    - November 21, 1954 "Good Turn Day-Goodwill Industries and Boy Scouts" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Mr. Amos R. Shields (Scout Executive of the Detroit Area Council of Boy Scouts of America), Mr. Harold H. McKinnon (Executive Secretary of the Goodwill Industries of Detroit), Miss Evelyn Herrala, Mr. John Bell (Scout Master in Detroit))
    - November 28, 1954 "Salvation Army" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Lt. Colonel T. M. Larsen (Divisional Commander), Major Oscar Agre, Envoy Arthur Truesdale, John Cunard (Harbor Lights Corps))
    - December 5, 1954 "Schools" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Roy E. Larsen (Publisher of Time, Incorporated and Chairman of the National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools))
    - December 12, 1954, "Israel's Judicial System", 3 tapes (Box 11)
      (Guests: Justice S. Zalman Cheshin (Deputy President of the Supreme Court of the State of Israel))
  - 1955
    - January 9, 1955 "Peaceful Atomic Development" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Walker L. Cisler (President, Detroit Edison Company and Chairman of Funds for Peaceful Atomic Development))
    - January 16, 1955 "United Nations" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Mr. Charles H. Mahoney (President of Great Lakes Mutual Life Insurance Co. and first regular delegate to United Nations from Michigan))
    - February 13, 1955 "Department of the Interior" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Douglas McKay (Secretary of the Department of the Interior))
    - May 1, 1955 "St. Lawrence Seaway" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Dr. N. R. Danielian (President of Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Association))
    - June 5, 1955 "Juvenile Delinquency" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Judge George Edwards)
    - June 19, 1955 "The Philippine Islands" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson (US Ambassador to the Philippines))
    - June 26, 1955 "Resume of Old Programs" (Box 11)
      (Guests: Bud Guest)
    - November 14, 1955 No title (Box 11)
  - Undated
    - Undated, No title (Box 11)